<EnemyInfo>
  <Name>Gunship Top</Name>
  <Description>
    Gunship top. Uses palette 7 regardless of enemy set. Does not use "speed", "speed 2", nor "Tilemap".
    Must be first enemy in room, followed by two gunship bottom enemies.
    Must be first enemy in enemy set during escape, due to hardcoding the location of the liftoff dust clouds in VRAM ($A2:ABC7).
    
    Sets the "intangible" and "process instruction" bits of initial "special".
    
    The initial Y position of this enemy is moved 25px upwards.
    If landing on Zebes from Ceres or if a demo not in set 0 is playing, Y position is set to 17px above Samus.
    If a demo in set 0 is playing, Samus' Y position is set to 472h.
    
    If landing on Zebes:
        Enemy moves itself, both gunship bottoms and Samus down at a rate of 4.5 px/frame until Y position 300h;
        then 2.5 px/frame until Y position 45Fh. *SMART handles adjusting Y position thresholds automatically*.
        Note that Samus' initial position is set by Crateria load station 12h,
        once the ship lands it will teleport Samus to the enemy's X position (+ 1).
    
    Spawns a palette FX object that modifies sprite palette 7 colour Fh.
    Uses load station 0 (hardcoded) for both post-landing save and manual save,
    Crateria load station 0 has a hardcoded ship icon spawned over the usual save icon in the map (see $82:B6BC).

    RAM:
        $0FA8: Function timer
        $0FAC: Hover index. Cycles between 0..3. Indexes $A2:A7CF hover movement table. Initialised to 0.
        $0FAE: Hover timer. Enemy processes next hover movement when this reaches zero. Initialised to 1. Reset value is 10h.
        $0FB0: Brakes timer in braking (0..10h). Enemy fixed Y position, initialised to enemy Y position when ejecting Samus, used as reference point for Samus entering/exiting transitions.
        $0FB2: Function. Initialised to $A80C if landing on Zebes, $AB60 if demo set 0 is playing, $A9BD otherwise.
  
  Submitted by PJ
  </Description>
  <Speed1>
  </Speed1>
  <Speed2>
  </Speed2>
  <Tilemap>
  </Tilemap>
</EnemyInfo>
