<EnemyInfo>
  <Name>Hiru</Name>
  <Description>
    A flat enemy that jumps up when samus is nearby then slowly floats down.

    The horizontal proximity in pixels to trigger movement is set at $A2:E039. Default in vanilla is 0x0050.

    When the enemy jumps up, it uses the quadradratic table ($A2:838F), and sets the the initial vertical speed such that it will jump up to reach the needed height. With a given acceleration, this means that there's a maximum total distance it properly move over (max spped in the table is about 17.5 px/frame). If the enemy needs to jump heigher than the table would produce, it will jump instantly to the max height instead.

    The upwards acceleration can be set at $A2:DFF3 and $A2:E096. Default in vanilla is 0x0200. With this default the max height is about 280 pixels (a little over 1 screen). If a heigher height is desired, the acceleration value can be lowered. Dropping the acceration to 0x0100 will increase the max height to about 540 pixels (a little over 2 screens). Lowering the speed less than that will increase the height roughly linearly.

    How high the enemy will jump is dependent on which float pattern it is using and how many times it will float. In vanilla the float patterns range from 0x1C to 0x20 pixels. The height each pattern will move is defined at the table at $A2:DF6A. The table is a list of pointers to the number to edit. If the value is modified, the move pattern will likely need to be changed respectively. The table has room for 6 entries, and the last is unused in vanilla.

    The float patterns lists are defined at $A2:DF6A. Again the entries are pointers to the data, and there are 6 entries with the last being unused in vanilla. The move pattern data is a list of pairs of words. All the coordinates are relative to the start of each float pattern (top middle). The first word is the X offset, the second is the Y offset. A value of 0x8000 indicates the end of the float pattern, and the enemy will either initialize another loop pattern or it will stop and rest on the ground. There is an unusual implementation of the indexer that prevents this table from having more than 0xFF entries (including the 0x8000 terminator).
  </Description>
  <Speed1>
    <Property>
      <Name>Float Pattern</Name>
      <Description>Which float pattern to use while falling down. The enemy will jump up heigh enough such in order to move through the specified float patterns.</Description>
      <Mask>0xFF00</Mask>
      <NameValues>
        <NameValue Value="0" Name="Radius: 0x0C, Height: 0x1E, Frames: 0x4A"/>
        <NameValue Value="1" Name="Radius: 0x20, Height: 0x1C, Frames: 0x4A"/>
        <NameValue Value="2" Name="Radius: 0x2D, Height: 0x20, Frames: 0x4A"/>
        <NameValue Value="3" Name="Radius: 0x11, Height: 0x1E, Frames: 0x5E"/>
        <NameValue Value="4" Name="Radius: 0x11, Height: 0x1E, Frames: 0x86"/>
      </NameValues>
    </Property>
    <Property>
      <Name>Float Count</Name>
      <Description>The number of times to use the float pattern while falling down. The enemy will jump up heigh enough such in order to move through the specified float patterns.</Description>
      <Mask>0x00FF</Mask>
    </Property>
  </Speed1>
  <Speed2>
    <Property>
      <Name>Delay</Name>
      <Description>Delay in frames to jump after Samus is in proximity.</Description>
      <Mask>0xFFFF</Mask>
    </Property>
  </Speed2>
  <Tilemap />
</EnemyInfo>
